Finding Aid for Boyne USA Resorts records, 1935-2005
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Boyne USA Resorts records 1935-2005, 1950s-2002
Boyne USA Resorts.
1 2-inch videotape
1 oversize folders
3 drawers
25 16mm films
19 oversize volumes
51 linear feet (in 54 boxes)
2010215 Bb 2
Michigan-based ski and golf corporation, operating twelve major resorts in North America; records consists of photographs, slides, video cassettes, films, sound recordings, promotional materials, biographical information on the corporation’s founder Everett F. Kircher, and miscellaneous office and topical files.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were received from the organization (donor no. 9323 ) in November 2010.
Periodic additions to the papers are expected.
The record group is open to research.
Boyne USA Resorts was founded by Everett F. Kircher whose real passion in life was skiing. As the owner of a small Studebaker car dealership in Detroit in the 1940s, Kircher would each year travel to the western United States in order to ski. The nuisance of traveling great distances prompted Kircher and two other enthusiasts in 1947 to purchase some property close by a small 500-foot mountain in northern Michigan. This $1 investment would become the Boyne Mountain ski and golf center and later Boyne USA.
Today, Boyne USA consists of twelve major ski and summer resorts: Boyne Mountain, Boyne Highlands, and The Inn at Bay Harbor in northern Michigan, Big Sky in Montana, Brighton Ski Bowl near Salt Lake City, Crystal Mountain and the Summit at Snoqualmie in Washington, Cypress Mountain in British Columbia, Loone Mountain in New Hampshire, and Sugarloaf and Sunday River, both in Maine. Boyne USA also owns and operates a scenic sky lift in Gatlinburg, Tennessee and ten golf courses in various states, including Michigan, Montana, and Florida.
Much of Kircher's success rested on both his business acumen and the innovations he brought to the industry. Kircher was credited with developing the first three- and four- person chairlifts and for installing the first detachable six-person chairlift in the United States. In 1964, Kircher installed the world's first three-person chairlift at Boyne Highlands and the world's first four-person chairlift at Boyne Mountain. In 1992, Boyne Mountain began operating the first six-person chairlift in the United States. Kircher also pioneered artificial snowmaking and co-invented the Boyne Snowmaker, the first efficient device for marginal temperature snowmaking. Kircher is also credited with developing many modern snow grooming techniques and equipment. Industry experts credit Kircher with inventing the idea of ski instruction. In the 1950s, he hired former Olympians Stein Erickson and Othmar Schneider to work at the resort's ski school and teach the latest teaching techniques to Boyne Mountain's skiers. Boyne Mountain, Boyne Highlands, and Big Sky continue to operate ski schools today.
In the late 1960s, Kircher worked to transform ski resorts into year-round recreational facilities by adding golf courses on his properties. Kircher began by building the Hemlock Golf Course at Boyne Mountain with his father's Ford farm tractor. Only after developing the nearby Harbor Highlands Ski Area into Boyne Highlands, however, did Kircher begin to invest seriously in golf. In 1970, the 18-hole Heather course, designed by Robert Trent Jones, Sr. opened. As of 2011, Boyne Resorts are home to eight world-class golf courses, including the award-winning courses at the Bay Harbor Golf Club.
Today, Boyne USA is the largest privately owned ski and golf corporation in America. The various resorts owned by Boyne now offer tennis, biking, hiking, horseback riding, and snowboarding, along with skiing and golf. The resorts also offer fine dining, spa facilities, retail shops, and luxury accommodations.
While Everett Kircher died on January 16, 2002 at the age of 85, his family remains actively involved in managing the thriving business he began in 1947.
The Boyne USA Resorts record group documents, through visual materials, scrapbooks and clippings, publications, and a scattering of administrative material, the development of northwestern Michigan as an important recreational center. The bulk of the collection consists of various visual media, photographs, photographic slides, albums, videotapes, motion pictures, promotional posters, display photographs, and design images of Boyne facilities.
The records have been arranged into the following series: Everett F. Kircher materials; Boyne USA publications and promotional materials; Topical files; Photographs; Negatives, Photographic Slides; Videotapes; Motion pictures; Art work; Architectural concept and promotional boards; Miscellaneous office records; Scrapbooks and Clippings, and Miscellaneous. The strength of the collection is in the various visual materials that document the development of Boyne USA Resorts from the founding of Boyne Mountain in 1947 to the early 21st century.
Subjects:
Big Sky Resort.; Boyne Highlands.; Boyne Mountain.; Boyne USA Resorts.; Gatlinburg Sky Lift.; Inn at Bay Harbor.; Kircher, Everett F.; Downhill skiing--Michigan.; Downhill skiing--Montana.; Golf--Michigan.; Golf--Montana.; Golf resorts--Michigan.; Golf resorts--Montana.; Recreation--Michigan.; Recreation--Montana.; Ski resorts--Michigan.; Ski resorts--Montana.; Bay Harbor (Mich.); Boyne Falls (Mich.); Big Sky (Mont.); Gatlinburg (Tenn.); Harbor Springs (Mich.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Kircher, Everett F.; Big Sky Resort.; Boyne Mountain.; Boyne Highlands.; Boyne USA Resorts.; Gatlinburg Sky Lift.; Inn at Bay Harbor.; Golf--Michigan.; Golf--Montana.; Ski resorts--Michigan.; Ski resorts--Montana.; Skiing--Michigan.; Skiing--Montana.; Bay Harbor (Mich.); Big Sky (Mont.); Boyne Falls (Mich.); Gatlinburg (Tenn.); Harbor Springs (Mich.)
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Boyne USA Resorts.; Radio advertising.
Genre Terms:
Color slides.; Motion pictures.; Negatives (photographic); Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videotapes.
- Everett F. Kircher materials
  The first series, Everett F. Kircher materials, documents the life of Everett F. Kircher, especially in regard to his founding of Boyne Mountain and management of the growth of the Boyne USA. Materials include biographical sketches, correspondence, newspaper clippings, and a copy of Kircher's autobiography.
  - Biographical articles; also (Box 1)
  - Biographical clippings (Box 1)
  - Newspaper obituaries and letters of tribute 2002 (Box 1)
  - Remembrances of EFK written on Boyne USA placemats (Box 1)
  - Copy of autobiography Everett Kircher, Michigan's Resort Pioneer; also miscellaneous drafts and other materials used in preparation of the book (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1965-2001 (scattered) (Box 1)
  - Kircher trust agreement as amended and restated (Box 1)
- Boyne USA publications and promotional material
  Boyne USA publications and promotional materials, the second series, contains information on Boyne USA's effort to promote its Michigan and Montana resorts. Marketing and sales materials include news releases, magazines, newspapers, brochures, advertisements, and postcards.
  - 40th Anniversary Logo (Box 1)
  - Boyne USA Resorts, 1984-1996 (Box 1)
  - Team Boyne News, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Boyne County newspaper, 1970s (Box 1)
  - Big Sky of Montana news releases 1973-1976, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Boynestadt Condos (Box 1)
  - Boyne USA news releases 1977, undated (Box 1)
  - Postcards of events and facilities (Box 1)
  - Northern Michigan publications with references to Boyne USA (Box 1)
  - Promotional brochures and advertisements, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Newspaper and periodical advertisements and announcements for Winter and Summer events, 2 volumes (Box 2)
  - Advertisements and brochures used as part of poster board displays, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Skiing and golfing magazines, most containing articles or advertisements from Boyne USA (Box 3)
  - Skiing and golfing magazines, most containing articles or advertisements from Boyne USA (Box 4)
    (continued)
- Topical files
  The third series, Topical Files, contains various non-visual materials. The series is organized alphabetically and primarily documents Bay Harbor, Big Sky, Boyne Highlands, and Boyne Mountain resorts. Some of the files also cover new business opportunities and some of Boyne's smaller properties.
  - Anniversary file (30th) 1979 (Box 5)
  - Argentina, possible business opportunities 1997 (Box 5)
  - Avalanche Bay Waterpark, impact study 2002, and construction progress report, 2004 (Box 5)
  - Bay Harbor
    - General, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Gold Club, plan for the offering of memberships 1997 (Box 5)
    - Tax roll 1996 (Box 5)
  - Big Sky, Montana
    - Big Sky Condominium Owners manual and various mailings 1976 (Box 5)
    - Big Sky Mountain Village, Master Plan Review 1999 (Box 5)
    - Big Sky Mountain Village, Overall Development Plan Amendment 2000 (Box 5)
    - Big Sky Ski Area Master Plan and related 1994 (Box 5)
    - Budget 1976 (Box 5)
    - Gallatin Canyon Planning Study, Final Report 1972 (Box 5)
    - Promotional material (Box 5)
    - Public Relations Biographical Data 1971, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Publication: Big Sky; From Indian Trails to the Tram, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Stillwater Owners Association 1975-1976 (Box 5)
    - Travel publications and agencies, correspondence with 1976 (Box 5)
  - Boyne Highlands Condominiums, architectural plans 1999 (Box 5)
  - Boyne Lift Tickets (Box 5)
  - Boyne Mountain Lodge, financial statements and related 1960-1963, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Boyne Realty, promotional material (Box 5)
  - Boyne South (Naples, Fla.)
    - Financial 1995-1996 (Box 5)
    - Golf Club summary report 1999 (Box 5)
  - Boyne USA By-Laws 1998 (Box 5)
  - Brighton Ski Resort 1994 (Box 5)
  - Chile (La Parva), possible business opportunities 2001 (Box 5)
  - Crystal Mountain Resort (Box 5)
  - Grand Georgian suite plans (Box 5)
  - Great Eastern Ski Life, Wasatch County, Utah 1994 (Box 5)
  - Haidbauer (Alex), letters to 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - Harbor Highlands Ski Club, financial statement 1962 (Box 5)
  - Hemlock condominium project, Boyne Mountain (organizational document, master agreement, lease draft, etc., 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Marriott International, proposed arrangement 2002 (Box 6)
  - (The) Moors Condominium Homesites (Box 6)
  - (The) Mountain Club
    - Purchaser Information Booklet (Box 6)
    - Site Plans and miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Mountain Grand Lodge and Spa, appraisal reports 2001, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Mountain Grand Lodge construction progress reports 2001, 2004 (Box 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1948-1991 (scattered) (Box 6)
  - Northern Michigan Golf Survey study circa 1989 (Box 6)
  - Organization booking files (Box 6)
    (sample)
  - Outstanding Business Leader Association award 2001 (Box 6)
  - Ramshead Condominium Project (purchaser information booklet, disclosure statement) 1993, undated, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Sky Lift Summit, 5-year plan (Box 6)
  - Snow to melt contest 2002 (Box 6)
  - Sundial Lodge at the Canyons, Utah, fulfillment documents 1998 (Box 6)
  - Timeshare miscellaneous (Box 6)
- Photographs
  Photographs, the fourth and largest series, documents the history of Boyne USA resorts from the founding of Boyne Mountain in 1947 to 2005. This is the largest and most comprehensive series in the collection and is organized into six sub-series. The first two sub-series make up the bulk of the series. The first sub-series, Albums of photographs, contains albums of color snapshots of Boyne events and activities. Photographic files, ca. 1940s-2000s consists of loose black-and-white and color prints organized by topically according to location. The following resort locations are documented in the sub-series: Boyne Mountain, Boyne Highlands, Big Sky, Bay Harbor, the Gatlinburg Sky Lift, Walloon Hills, and Thunder Mountain. There is also a significant portion of the Photographic files, ca. 1940s-2000s where the location is unidentified. In this case the photographs are organized alphabetically by subject. Subjects include aerial views, buildings, skiing, golf, ski races, golf tournaments, conferences, entertainment, dining, construction, award ceremonies, and people. Additional sub-series are: Photographs Used in Pictorial History of Boyne, Various Topics, Promotional photographs, and Framed color photographs.
  - Albums of Photographs
    - Easter Sunday and Spring Fashion Show April 1990 (Box 7)
    - July 15, 1990 Byron Nelson; monument dedication; Donald Ross course opening (Box 7)
    - WLLZ and Hawaiian Tropic Weekend circa 1990 (Box 7)
    - July 15, 1991, Everett Kircher's 75th birthday; and monument dedication (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous events (Box 7)
    - Cubs Wives Celebrity Golf Scramble June 1992 (Box 7)
    - Skiing and other activities (Box 7)
    - Combined activities 1989-1990 (Box 7)
    - Golf course photos 1996, 2 volumes (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous: skiing and golf 1990 (with some earlier) (Box 8)
    - Various events 1991 (Box 8)
    - Winter groundbreaking event (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous events and publicity photos (Box 9)
    - Big Sky, Montana (Box 9)
    - Snowboard; Pro Tour Event Photos (Box 9)
    - Winter Events, 3 volumes (Box 10)
    - Winter Events, 3 volumes (Box 11)
    - Winter Events, 4 volumes (Box 12)
    - Summer Events, 2 volumes (Box 13)
    - Color prints of Boyne USA facilities (Volume 16)
    - Albums of snapshots of golfing events and golfing personalities 1980s, 2 volumes
      (include snapshots of Sam Snead, Governor James Blanchard)
      - Albums of snapshots of golfing events and golfing personalities 1980s (Volume 17)
      - Albums of snapshots of golfing events and golfing personalities 1980s (Volume 18)
  - Photographic file circa 1940s-2000s
    - Bay Harbor
      - Construction (Box 14)
      - General, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Big Sky, Montana development
      - Accident During Construction (Box 14)
      - Construction 1972 (Box 14)
      - Dedication, March, 17-19 (Box 14)
      - General, 8 folders (Box 14)
      - Golf (Chet Huntley and Arnold Palmer) (Box 14)
      - Helicopter--Setting Steel for Ski Lifts (Box 14)
      - Horseback Riding (Box 14)
      - Huntley Lodge, 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Legislative Day January 27, 1974 (Box 14)
      - Lone Mountain Guest Ranch, 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Meadow Village
        - Condos, Fall (Box 14)
        - Condos, Winter (Box 14)
        - Commercial Area (Box 14)
      - Opening Day December 15, 1978 (Box 14)
      - Scenery, Fall and Winter (Box 14)
    - Boyne Highlands
      - Arthur Hills (Box 15)
      - Bartley House (Box 15)
      - Boy-Girl Story (Extra Slides) (Box 15)
      - Chairlift (Box 15)
      - Construction (Box 15)
      - Convention & Ski Center (Box 15)
      - Conventions (Box 15)
      - Cross Country (Box 15)
      - Families & Kids (Box 15)
      - Fishing, Sailing, Etc. (Box 15)
      - General (Box 15)
      - Girls & Girls (Box 15)
      - Golf (Box 15)
      - Golf Academy, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Golf Course (Box 15)
      - Greystone (Box 15)
      - Heather Highlands Inn (Box 15)
      - History (Box 15)
      - Lodge
        - Interior (Box 15)
        - Summer (Box 15)
        - Winter (Box 15)
      - Miss Universe 1976 (Box 15)
      - Personalities (Box 15)
      - Personnel (Box 15)
      - Ski School (Box 15)
      - Skiing (Box 15)
      - Social Entertainment (Box 15)
      - Spring Skiing (Box 15)
      - Teens (Box 15)
      - Young Americans (Box 15)
    - Boyne Mountain
      - Activities, Fashion Shows, etc. (Box 15)
      - Aerials, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Air Academy (Box 15)
      - Beach House (Box 15)
      - Boynestadt, Construction (Box 15)
      - Broom Hockey (Box 15)
      - Building, Outdoor, Winter (Box 15)
      - Chairlift (Box 15)
      - Children Fishing (Box 15)
      - Cliff Dweller (Box 15)
      - Commercial Village (Box 15)
      - Complex (Box 15)
      - Conventions, Summer 1968 (Box 15)
      - Country, Scenic (Box 15)
      - Cussa Certification 1968 (Box 15)
      - Entertainment (Box 15)
      - Figure Skating (Box 15)
      - Freeman File (Box 15)
      - General (Box 15)
      - Golf (Box 15)
      - Golf Course Building Maintenance (Box 15)
      - Hemlock Course (Box 15)
      - Lodge, Summer 1975 (Box 15)
      - Mountain Club (Box 15)
      - Mountain Grand Lodge and Spa Groundbreaking 2000 (Box 15)
      - Mountain Village (Box 15)
      - Nastar, Heuga, Everett K, Hans (Box 15)
      - Negatives, General (Box 16)
      - New Years Eve 1968-1969 (Box 16)
      - Pro and Ski Races (Box 16)
      - Schneider & Ski School (Box 16)
      - Services (Box 16)
      - Ski Week (Box 16)
      - Skiing (Box 16)
      - Special Dinner (Box 16)
      - Special Events (Box 16)
      - Steak Story (Box 16)
    - Gatlinburg Sky Lift
      - General (Box 16)
    - Thunder Mountain
      - General (Box 16)
      - Aerials (Box 16)
      - Manager (Box 16)
      - Racing (Box 16)
      - Seaton, Lynn 1968-1969 (Box 16)
    - Walloon Hills
      - Manager (Box 16)
      - Ski Patrol (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous (Location unclear)
      - 40th Anniversary (Box 16)
      - Aerial
        - Views of properties and ski slopes, 2 folders (Box 16)
        - Aerial--Ski Slope (Box 16)
      - Airplanes (Box 16)
      - Awards
        - Celebrations (Box 16)
        - Children (Box 16)
        - Kircher (giving and receiving) (Box 16)
        - Presentations (Box 16)
        - Ski Patrol (Box 16)
      - Billboard Artwork (Box 16)
      - Boyne City Hydro Plant (Box 16)
      - Boyne Country Sports (Box 16)
      - Boyne South (Box 16)
      - Broom Hockey (Box 16)
      - Buildings, exterior (Box 16)
      - Buildings, interior
        - Dining (Box 16)
        - General (Box 16)
      - Celebrations, indoors, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Celebrations, outdoors (Box 16)
      - Children
        - General (Box 16)
        - Close-ups (Box 16)
      - Convention & Exhibits (Box 16)
      - Conferences, programs (Box 16)
      - Construction
        - General (Box 16)
        - Floor models (Box 16)
      - Couples (Box 17)
      - Country Club (Box 17)
      - Cross Country (Box 17)
      - Dining
        - Chefs, food (Box 17)
        - General (Box 17)
        - Picnic, informal (Box 17)
      - Dining room, color prints (Box 17)
      - Dog sledding (Box 17)
      - Figure skating
        - Adults (Box 17)
        - Children (Box 17)
      - Fireworks display 2001, 2003 (Box 17)
      - Fishing (Box 17)
      - Flick, Jim (Box 17)
      - Fly Boyne (Box 17)
      - Golf
        - 1960s (Box 17)
        - General, b&w (Box 17)
        - General (color prints), 2 folders (Box 17)
        - Great Scot Golf Course (Box 17)
        - Kircher Cup
          - 1980s (Box 17)
          - 1984 (Box 17)
          - 1985 (Box 17)
          - 1986 (Box 17)
        - Pro Golf Shop (Box 17)
        - Tournaments (Box 17)
      - Groups
        - General (Box 17)
        - Skiers
          - Casual (Box 17)
          - Posed (Box 17)
      - High Speed Chairlifts (Box 17)
      - Howe, Gordie (Box 17)
      - Individuals, 3 folders (Box 17)
      - Kircher, Everett
        - 77th Birthday, Boyne Mountain Resort July 26, 1993 (Box 17)
        - Family members (Box 17)
        - Portraits (Box 17)
        - With family (Box 17)
        - Hunting and Fishing (Box 17)
        - With others (Box 17)
      - Milliken, William and Helen (Box 17)
      - Miscellaneous
        - Black and White Prints, 3 folders (Box 18)
        - Color Prints, 3 folders (Box 18)
        - Early Photographs (Box 18)
      - Miss Universe 1975 (Box 18)
      - Negatives, Contact Prints, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Night Skiing (Box 18)
      - Personalities (Erich Bader, Karl and Margo Plattner, Dana Anderson, Al Litzenberger, and Gerald R. Ford) (Box 18)
      - Postcards (Box 18)
      - Press Photo, Summer (Box 18)
      - Property Development 1968 (Box 18)
      - Pro Shops (Box 18)
      - Racing
        - Action photos (Box 18)
        - Competitions
          - Action photos (Box 18)
          - Boyne (Box 18)
          - Can Am (Box 18)
          - Grand Prix (Box 18)
          - Hanson Challenge (Box 18)
          - Hart (Box 18)
          - Head (Box 18)
          - Heuer (Box 18)
          - K2 (Box 18)
          - MDSC (Box 18)
          - Nastar (Box 18)
          - Piz Buin (Box 18)
          - Pro Ski Races (Box 18)
          - Rieker (Box 18)
          - Slalom Event (Box 18)
          - White Star (Box 19)
        - Cross Country (Box 19)
        - General (Box 19)
      - Real Estate (Box 19)
      - Resort Construction (Box 19)
      - Room Interiors (Box 19)
      - Scenic views (Box 19)
      - Skiing
        - Action (Box 19)
        - Cross Country (Box 19)
        - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 19)
        - Professionals (Box 19)
        - Novices (Box 19)
        - Spring Skiing (Box 19)
        - Views from a Distance (Box 19)
      - Ski Clubs (Box 19)
      - Ski Lessons, School (Box 19)
      - Ski lifts, 2 folders (Box 19)
      - Ski, Falls (Box 19)
      - Ski Patrol (Box 20)
      - Ski Teams (Box 20)
      - Ski Parties (Box 20)
      - Snow machines (Box 20)
      - Snow Melt (Box 20)
      - Snow sculptures (Box 20)
      - Snowmobile, Ski-doo (Box 20)
      - Staff (Box 20)
      - Summer Activities (Box 20)
      - Swimming Pool (Box 20)
      - Tennis (Box 20)
      - Trains (Box 20)
      - Tree removal (preparing slope for skiing) (Box 20)
      - Visitors Center (Box 20)
      - Winchester Memorial (Box 20)
      - Winter Activities (Box 20)
      - Winter Carnival 1974 (Box 20)
      - Winter Carnival 1975 (Box 20)
  - Photographs Used in Pictorial History of Boyne USA (assembled from various sources)
    - Everett Kircher, alone and at social gatherings (Box 21)
    - Copy prints of historical photos from the collection of the US Ski Hall of Fame (Box 21)
    - Ski, skate and golf celebrities (Box 21)
    - Social events (Box 21)
    - Outdoors -- skiing, skating, and other event (Box 21)
    - Snapshots (Box 21)
    - Various groups (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 21)
  - Various Topics
    (formerly framed photographs with attached descriptions)
    - Dorothea Blakeslee in 1935 ski attire, 2 photographs (Box 21)
    - Chuck Moll tees it up in a publicity photo, Winter 1972 (Box 21)
    - Margy Jurmo practicing at Boyne Mountain Ice Rink, Summer 1959 (Box 21)
    - Gerald R. Ford (Box 21)
      (two photos on one mat)
    - William Coonrod outside ticket booth (Box 21)
    - Boyne Mountain Golf Academy circa 1964 (Box 21)
    - Original pool, before glass walls circa 1951 (Box 21)
    - Original Sun Valley single chair installed, Sky Lift, Gatlinburg, Tenn. (Box 21)
    - Rocky Mountain view, color print (Box 21)
    - Everett Kircher holding large fish, color print (Box 21)
    - Skier performing trick (Box 21)
    - Woman getting out of indoor pool with winter view showing through the windows (Box 21)
    - Unidentified man on ladder, 3 images (Box 21)
    - Line-up of skiers, wearing same jacket, perhaps members of a ski club (Box 21)
    - Stein Erickson with others outside faux pier behind banner "S.S. Goodtimer" (Box 21)
    - Skiers outside ski shop (Box 21)
    - Line-up of men on skis (Box 21)
    - Kircher Motors dealership, street view (Box 21)
    - Aerial Photographs of Bay Harbor (Box 21)
    - Aerial Photographs of Boyne Highlands and Boyne Mountain (Box 21)
    - Everett Kircher and chef holding birthday cake with design of the Boyne Mountain golf course (Box 22)
    - Uploading view, Sky Lift, Gatlinburg, Tenn. (Box 22)
    - Sky Lift ticket window 1950s (Box 22)
    - Early North Boyne double chair (Box 22)
    - The first slope December 1955 (Box 22)
      (photo by V. Haynes)